<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ember Add On on Blog</title>
    <link>https://bennycwong.github.io/tags/ember-add-on/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ember Add On on Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 22:23:24 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://bennycwong.github.io/tags/ember-add-on/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing ember-router-scroll</title>
      <link>https://bennycwong.github.io/post/2016-08-01-ember-router-scroll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 22:23:24 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bennycwong.github.io/post/2016-08-01-ember-router-scroll/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Editorial Note:&lt;/strong&gt; I originally wrote this post for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://engineering.dollarshaveclub.com/introducing-ember-router-scroll/&#34;&gt;DSC Engineering Blog&lt;/a&gt;.  Head over to there and check out the original.  While you’re there, have a look at the other articles.
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here at Dollar Shave Club, we rely heavily on open-source technologies.
We chose Ember.js as our front end framework to build our web experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By design, Ember maintains scroll position when transitioning between routes.
This makes sense for typical single page applications (SPAs), as SPAs tend to be rendered with nested views.
If a nested view is 1000px down the page, when you enter that nested route, you would want to still be 1000px down the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, our design calls for rendering pages in a non-nested fashion.
The default Ember behavior of maintaining scroll position is no longer the right user experience (UX).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/4430436/17122972/0a1fe454-5295-11e6-937f-f1f5beab9d6b.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Default ember scroll behavior&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, one of the first pieces of Ember code written here at Dollar Shave Club is a way to scroll the user to the top of the page on route transition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this presents a new UX problem.
While scroll-to-top is good UX for entering a new route, a user would expect to maintain scroll position when going back and forward in the browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To solve this problem, we created a &lt;code&gt;scrollMap&lt;/code&gt; to store scroll states on &lt;code&gt;willTransition&lt;/code&gt;, a hook that gets called whenever a user leaves a route.
In the &lt;code&gt;didTransition&lt;/code&gt; hook, we check to see if the transition was triggered by a browser history event (&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Events/popstate&#34;&gt;popstate event&lt;/a&gt;).
If a popstate is detected, the user is sent to the scroll position in the &lt;code&gt;scrollMap&lt;/code&gt; instead of the top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cloud.githubusercontent.com/assets/4430436/17122970/07c1a3a0-5295-11e6-977f-37eb955d95b1.gif&#34; alt=&#34;ember-router-scroll behavior&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check it out here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dollarshaveclub/ember-router-scroll&#34;&gt;ember-router-scroll&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>